Guide to the Florence and Henry Wald Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Hospice Movement Subject Files, 1963-1980; Series II
  - United States, Veterans Administration, 1978-1979, undated (Box 17, Folder 103)
    See also: Series II. Hospice Movement Subject Files, 1963-1980 Folder 106
  - University of Chicago Hospitals and Clinics, Registry of Tumors [Chicago, IL], 1976, undated (Box 18, Folder 104)
  - University of North Carolina Health Services Research Center [Chapel Hill, NC], Circa 1978 (Box 18, Folder 105)
  - Wadsworth Medical Center Palliative Care Unit [Los Angeles, CA], 1975-1978, undated (Box 18, Folder 106)
    See also:Series II. Hospice Movement Subject Files, 1963-1980 Folder 103
  - Washington Hospice Society [District of Columbia], 1978-1979, undated (Box 18, Folder 107)
  - Wonderful Enlightenment Mountain [Talmage, CA], 1976 (Box 18, Folder 108)
- Yale School of Nursing Files, 1956-1979; Series III
  Arranged alphabetically, Yale School of Nursing Files documents Wald's career as a faculty member and dean of the school. The series includes correspondence, course materials, curriculum planning, proposals, and clippings, all pertaining to the School of Nursing. Transcripts for a three part radio series from 1959 on the role of nursing in modern society are listed under "Yale Reports," the title of the radio show. "Oncology nursing core course," and "Seminar on the Chronically Ill" document Wald's efforts to incorporate the teaching of care for the terminally ill into the School of Nursing curriculum.
  - Conn, Harold J., 1971, undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Curriculum planning for advanced program, 1956-1957, undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Fabric, Bruce, 1969-1979, undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Notes and clippings [miscellaneous], 1968-1969, undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Oncology nursing core course, 1974-1975, undated (Box 19, Folder 5 - 6)
  - Oncology Nursing Programs in Medical Centers [proposal to National Cancer Institute], 1974-1975 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Seminar on the Chronically Ill, 1968-1970, undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - "Yale Reports" [radio show], Function of Nursing in Modern Society, 1959 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Yale University Media Design Studio, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 10)
- Writings, 1955-1979; Series IV
  Writings includes articles, papers, speeches, presentations, and a book written or edited by Florence and/or Henry Wald. The series is arranged alphabetically by author and title and folders include writings, correspondence and other research materials which pertain to each work. The writings concern the hospice movement and other nursing subjects. "Hospice Care for Dying Patients," "Hospice, Inc.: From Dream to Reality," and "Hospice: A Way of Caring for the Terminally Ill" describe the inception and programs of Hospice, Inc. One folder of correspondence regarding several speaking engagements is filed at the beginning of the series. Untitled presentations at conferences and other events are listed by location at the end of the Florence Wald writings.
  - Wald, Florence
    - Correspondence [re: speaking engagements], 1965, 1972-1976, undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - "Alternatives in Care for the Terminally Ill", 1977-1978, undated (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - "Alumnae Day Speech" [Yale School of Nursing], 1959 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - American Nurse [editorial], 1978-1979, undated (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - "The Community and the Returning Patient" [Panel discussion for Connecticut Association for Mental Health, Inc.], 1958 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - "Development of Nursing Practice Theory", 1963 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Development of Patient Care Research [monograph edited with Robert C. Leonard]
      - Correspondence, notes, and drafts, 1968-1969, undated (Box 20, Folder 7 - 8)
      - Typescript, [1968] (Box 20, Folder 9 - 11)
    - "Effective Nurse-Patient Relationships", 1957 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - "Emerging Nursing Practice", 1965-1966 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - "Faculty Participation in Nursing Practice", 1966 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - "Hospice Care for Dying Patients" [written with Joan Craven], 1975 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - "Hospice, Inc.: From Dream to Reality", 1972 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - "Hospice: A Way of Caring for the Terminally Ill", 1972 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - "Memorandum to an Incumbent Dean" [speech made upon receiving an honorary degree from the University of Bridgeport School of Nursing], 1967 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - "The Metamorphosis of the Public Health Nurse", 1964 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - "The Nurse and the Patient with Tuberculosis in the Hospital Setting", undated (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - "A Nurse's Study of Care of Dying Patients", 1969-1970 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - "The Nursing Process", 1965 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - "Practical Problems in Faculty Research Development", 1964 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - "Responsibility and the Nurse's Accountability to the Dying Patient", 1974 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - "Responsibility of the VNA in a Comprehensive Mental Health Program", 1959 (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - "A Study on the Accumulation of a Counselor to a Residential Treatment Center for Schizophrenic Children" [Master's thesis], 1955 (Box 21, Folder 26)
    - "To Everything There is a Season and a Time to Every Purpose", 1969, undated (Box 21, Folder 27)
    - "Towards Development of a Nursing Practice Theory", 1964 (Box 21, Folder 28)
    - "Using the Nursing Education Product", 1966 (Box 21, Folder 29)
    - "Yale and Nursing Education", undated (Box 21, Folder 30)
    - Untitled presentations
      - Human Values Conference, West Orange, NJ, 1979, undated (Box 21, Folder 31)
      - Medical Board Luncheon, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 32)
      - Norwalk Hospital School of Nursing [commencement address], 1962 (Box 21, Folder 33)
      - St. Louis University Medical Center Symposium on Home Health Care, 1978-1979 (Box 21, Folder 34)
      - United Hospital, Portchester, 1976 (Box 21, Folder 35)
      - Yale University School of Nursing[speech to Medical Staff], 1964 (Box 21, Folder 36)
    - Miscellaneous writings, 1965-1976, undated (Box 21, Folder 37)
  - Wald, Florence and Henry
    - "The Hospice Movement: A Backwards Glance at its First Two Decades" [written with Zelda Foster], 1978 (Box 21, Folder 38)
    - "The Hospice Movement as a Health Care Reform"
      - Correspondence and research materials, 1978-1979, undated (Box 21, Folder 39)
      - Typescript, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - Wald, Henry
    - "A Hospice for Terminally Ill Patients" [Master's Thesis]
      - Research materials, 1968-1972, undated (Box 21, Folder 41 - 42)
      - Typescript, 1970-1971, undated (Box 21, Folder 43 - 44)
    - "Rethinking Care for the Terminally Ill; Hospice: Reason, Responsibility, and Reaction"
      - Correspondence and notes, 1977-1978 (Box 21, Folder 45)
      - Typescripts, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 46)
- Research Notebooks, 1969-1971; Series V
  Conditions Governing Access
  Researchers must sign the Access Agreement for the Florence Wald Notebooks to examine Series V, boxes 22-28.
  The series primarily consists of sixteen volumes of notes, correspondence, transcripts of team meetings, interviews with patients, and other materials documenting the two year grant funded research that became known as "A Nurse's Study of Care of Dying Patients." In exchange for palliative care, approximately forty individuals allowed Wald and her team to take extensive notes on their care. The research team used the lessons learned in the study as a basis for the formation of Hospice, Inc. Arranged in loose chronological order, the volumes chart the progress of study and hold valuable evidence of the circumstances surrounding dying patients. A bibliography used while conducting the study is listed at the beginning of the series.
  - Bibliography, [1969-1971] (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Patient information sheets, [1969-1971]
    See: Restricted Files, Box 29, Folder 2
  - Patient list, [1971]
    See: Restricted Files, Box 29, Folder 3
  - Patient permission sheets, [1969]
    See: Restricted Files, Box 29, Folder 4
  - Team members, 1969 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Volumes 1-3, 1969 January-September (Box 22, Folder 3 - 12)
  - Volumes 4-5, 1969 October-1970 February (Box 23, Folder 13 - 23)
  - Volumes 6-7, 1970 February-May (Box 24, Folder 24 - 38)
  - Volumes 8-9, 1970 May-September (Box 25, Folder 39 - 51)
  - Volumes 10-12, 1970 July-October (Box 26, Folder 52 - 67)
  - Volumes 13-14, 1970 November-1971 March (Box 27, Folder 68 - 80)
  - Volumes 15-16, 1971 March-December (Box 28, Folder 81 - 90)
- Restricted Files
  Patient information is restricted until January 1, 2050.
  - Hospice, Inc. files
    - Home Care Program
      - Patient information, 1974-1975, undated (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Research notebooks
    - Patient information sheets (Open 2046 Jan 1), [1969-1971] (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Patient list (Open 2046 Jan 1), [1971] (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Patient permission sheets (Open 2046 Jan 1), [1969] (Box 29, Folder 4)
- Additional material, Accession 2001-M-047
  The accession consists of correspondence, newsletters, clippings, brochures, minutes, writings, proposals, reports, and other miscellaneous materials, which are arranged alphabetically under three sections: Correspondence and topical files; Prison hospices; and Writings. The accession supplements the first three series of the main accession and adds documentation relating to Florence Wald's work with prison hospices.
  The Correspondence and topical files reflect Florence Wald's association with Hospice, Inc. from the 1970s until 2000. Of particular interest are documents relating staff complaints about the administration of the hospice, including but not limited to, correspondence, by-laws, complaints, and incorporation documents from the Citizens Concerned for Compassionate Hospice Care (CCCHC). The CCCHC, an organization in which Wald and other hospice founders were leaders, was established in 1999 to protest the move of Hospice, Inc. from its original site. The series also contains correspondence, both personal and professional, from Cicely Saunders and others at St. Christopher's Hospice in England, as well as information from St. Christopher's conferences in 1980 and 1982, both of which were attended by Florence and Henry Wald. Materials relating to the International Work Group on Death, Dying, and Bereavement consist primarily of mass mailings, financial documents, member listings, and biographies, and also contain information from a twenty-fifth anniversary convention in Boulder, Colorado, as well as minutes, surveys, and correspondence from the first years of the group's incorporation. The material relating to the Yale School of Nursing consists of administrative documents from Wald's years as dean and other correspondence, newsletters, and reports from subsequent years as Wald served on faculty and as dean emerita. Also in the series are materials relating to Florence Wald's efforts to help create hospices in prisons, a movement begun in 1992 by Fleet Maull, who was a Colorado inmate at the time.
  - Correspondence and Topical Files
    - General correspondence, 1979-1996, undated (Box 1, Folder 1 - 3)
    - Accumulated Loss, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - "American Institute of Life Threatening Illness" [correspondence], 1988-1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Bailey and the arts, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Byock, Ira [correspondence], 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Byock, Ira [paper against physician-assisted suicide], undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Chan, Lo-Yi, "Hospice: A New Building Type to Comfort the Dying", 1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Citizens Concerned for Compassionate Hospice Care, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 10 - 11)
    - Clippings, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - State of Connecticut, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - State of Connecticut [Licensure of hospices], undated (Box 2, Folder 14 - 15)
    - Corless, Inge Baer, 1967, [1979], 1985 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Decedent Affairs Committee, 1997 June-1999 Jan, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Diagnostic Related Group case study [workshop by Donna Diers], 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Free-standing hospices, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Grant proposals, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Halloray, Edward, [1992?]-1996 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Hospice brochures, undated (Box 2, Folder 22 - 24)
    - Hospice Council of Connecticut, 1996, 1997, undated (Box 2, Folder 25 - 26)
    - The Hospice History Project [Clark and Small], undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Hospice, Inc.
      - General, 1972-1995, undated (Box 3, Folder 28 - 30)
      - Administration policies and procedures, undated (Box 3, Folder 31 - 32)
      - Developments, 1993, undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - First American Hospice (Lack, et al.) [corrections by Florence Wald], undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - Move, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Hospice standards, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - International Working Group on Death, Dying, and Bereavement
      - General, undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
      - Assumptions and principles regarding bereavement, undated (Box 3, Folder 38 - 39)
      - Bibliography, undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
      - History, incorporation, and bylaws, undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
      - Meeting, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 42)
      - Rocky Mountain meeting, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 43)
      - Membership, undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
      - Update, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 45)
      - Products and Omega Foundation, undated (Box 4, Folder 46)
      - Psychosocial, ethics, death, and art, undated (Box 4, Folder 47)
      - Publications, undated (Box 4, Folder 48)
      - Twenty-five years of mutual support, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - John D. Thompson Hospice [Institute for Education, Training and Research], 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Johnson, Linda, undated (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Kron, Joan, undated (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Last acts, undated (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Lost and Found School of Thought, undated (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Manthey, Marie [Creative nurse management], 1990 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Medicare reimbursement, undated (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Miscellaneous background material, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - National Congress of Thanatology, undated (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - National Hospice Organization, undated (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - National League for Nursing, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - News articles, 1993, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - O'Connor, Patrice [St Luke's Hospice-primarily reports on palliative care], 1990-1991, undated (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Peppers, Max and Anita, 1978-1998, undated (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Reid and Riege [law office], undated (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Response to pain, undated (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Ross, Elisabeth Kübler, 1976, 1991-1997 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - St. Christopher's Hospice
      - General, undated (Box 5, Folder 67)
      - "Bar Mitzvah", 1980 June (Box 5, Folder 68)
      - Conference, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 69)
      - Correspondence
        - 1970-1994 (Box 5, Folder 70 - 72)
        - 1995-1997 (Box 6, Folder 73)
      - Newsletters, flyers, annual review, undated (Box 6, Folder 74)
    - Saunders, Cicely [articles including "The Hospice: Its Meaning to Patients and Their Physicians," "Facing Death," and "The Evolution of the Hospices;" a chapter from her book, Death and Dying: Current Issues in the Treatment of the Dying Person; a telegram to Florence Wald; and "Someone to Watch Over Me," by David Clark, an article about Cicely Saunders.], 1969, 1980-1988, 1991, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 75)
    - Schmieding, Norma J., undated (Box 6, Folder 76)
    - Spiritual-ethical background papers, undated (Box 6, Folder 77)
    - Spiritual resources, undated (Box 6, Folder 78 - 79)
    - Stratford Visiting Nurse Association [award for Florence Wald], 2000 April 11 (Box 6, Folder 80)
    - Thompson, A. Siobhan, undated (Box 6, Folder 81)
    - VITAS Healthcare Corp., undated (Box 6, Folder 82)
    - Wald, Henry [denial of care], 2000-2001 (Box 6, Folder 83)
    - Wessel, Morris, undated (Box 6, Folder 84 - 85)
    - Yale-New Haven Hospital [response to death training materials], undated (Box 6, Folder 86)
    - Yale School of Nursing
      - General, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 87)
      - Administrative materials, 1965-1969 (Box 7, Folder 88)
      - Correspondence, 1983-1989 (Box 7, Folder 89)
      - Proposed doctoral program in nursing, undated (Box 7, Folder 90)
      - Reports, 1959-1979 (Box 7, Folder 91)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 7, Folder 92)
  - Prison hospices
    - General, undated (Box 8, Folder 93)
    - Clippings, undated (Box 8, Folder 94 - 96)
    - Community resources, undated (Box 8, Folder 97)
    - Conferences, undated (Box 8, Folder 98)
    - Conferences: "Finding Common Ground", 1998 (Box 8, Folder 99 - 100)
    - Contacts, undated (Box 8, Folder 101)
    - Correspondence, 1993-2000, undated (Box 8, Folder 102 - 105)
    - Crime research organizations, 1997-1998, undated (Box 9, Folder 106)
    - Demographics, undated (Box 9, Folder 107)
    - Directory, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 108)
    - Feasibility study, undated (Box 9, Folder 109)
    - Financial support, undated (Box 9, Folder 110)
    - First National Conference on Death and Dying in Prisons and Jails, undated (Box 9, Folder 111)
    - Grant proposals, undated (Box 9, Folder 112)
    - Gross, Donalyn, undated (Box 9, Folder 113)
    - HIV, undated (Box 9, Folder 114 - 117)
    - HIV [Doe vs. Meachum], undated (Box 9, Folder 118 - 119)
    - Hospice Nurses Association [newsletter article], undated (Box 9, Folder 120)
    - Interview with Florence Wald, undated (Box 9, Folder 121)
    - Literature review, undated (Box 9, Folder 122)
    - Maull, Fleet, undated (Box 10, Folder 123)
    - Meetings, undated (Box 10, Folder 124)
    - Notes, 1995-1996 (Box 10, Folder 125)
    - Printed material, undated (Box 10, Folder 126)
    - Localities
      - Colorado, undated (Box 10, Folder 127)
      - Illinois, undated (Box 10, Folder 128)
      - Maryland, undated (Box 10, Folder 129)
      - Texas, undated (Box 10, Folder 130)
    - Prison visits
      - General, undated (Box 10, Folder 131)
      - Garner, Newtown, Connecticut, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 132)
      - York, Niantic, Connecticut, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 133)
    - Reports, undated (Box 11, Folder 134 - 139)
    - Schweitzer Foundation, undated (Box 11, Folder 140)
    - Statistics, undated (Box 11, Folder 141)
    - Surveys and questionnaires, undated (Box 11, Folder 142)
    - Testimonies, undated (Box 11, Folder 143)
  - Writings
    - General, undated (Box 11, Folder 144)
    - Hospice paper, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 145)
- Additional material, Accession 2006-M-054
  The accession consists of two copies of a transcript of an oral history interview of Florence Wald, conducted by Monica Mills for the Connecticut Women's Hall of Fame archives, June 10, 2003.
  - Oral history interview transcripts, 2003 June 10 (Box 1)
- Additional material, 1964-2009; Accession 2009-M-050
  Arrangement
  The accession is arranged as received from the donor.
  The accession comprises correspondence, writings, presentations, organizational materials, and printed ephemera relating to Florence Wald's work and research in hospice care, terminal illness, and the nursing profession.
  - Aging at Home, Inc.
    - Board minutes, 2002-2006 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Mission statements, timelines, and finances, 2002-2006 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Membership, demographic information, and public relations, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence to and from Florence Wald, 1987-2009 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
  - Florence Wald writings, 1984-2002 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Connecticut Nurses' Association printed materials, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Yale School of Nursing Creative Writing Award for Nurses information and application, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Yale announcements about Florence Wald, 2000-2005 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - History of hospice care essay and drafts, Circa 2001 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Yale School of Nursing history, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Other Paths to a Career in Health Care" essay, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Jorgensen, Judith Mead, masters thesis, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Peaceful death papers, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Wald, Henderson, McBride, and Halloran, "Notes on Peaceful Death", 1998 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Chapter 1. Background of research in nursing practice," typescript, Circa 1990-2009 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "In Face of a Terminal Illness," various draft pages, Circa 1990-2009 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Wald, Lillian, The House on Henry Street (1915), notes and introduction, Circa 1990-2009 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Florence Wald correspondence, 1988-2000 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Response to Santos paper on YSN, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Speeches, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Santos, Brenda, paper on the Yale School of Nursing's 1956 curriculum crisis, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Foster, Zelda, and Florence Wald, "A Crossroads", Circa 1999 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Bulkin, Wald, and Butler papers, 1964-1994 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Faculty seminar on medical ethics, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Nursing and the continuity of care, presentation, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Craven, Joan, and Florence Wald, "Hospice Care for Dying Patients," reprint and correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Writings on hospice care in the U.S. by Florence Wald, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - "Death and the Quest for Meaning," chapter drafts, Circa 1987-1996 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - "Palliative Treatment and Curative Treatment," draft and notes, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Wald biovignette, Circa 2001 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - "The Hospice Movement as a Health Care Reform," drafts and correspondence, Circa 1979 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Sigma Theta Tau papers for Virginia Henderson festschrift, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Hospices in the changing health care system, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Albert Schweitzer International Symposium on Global Health, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - "Hospice Care as a Path through the Life Cycle," draft, Circa 1990-2009 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - A new way of care at the end of life, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
  - Miscellaneous Wald writings, 2001-2002 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Postcards, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - "Finding Common Ground for Hospice Care in Connecticut Prisions," workbook and notes, 2000-2001 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Thresholds, a volunteer writing tutor program for prisoners, forms and poetry of inmate A.R., 1997 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "Griswold Life Tales," interview with Florence Wald concerning her life, 2003-2004
    Disc 2 was not received by the repository, only discs 1, 3A-B, and 4.
    - Track listings for discs 1, 3A-B, and 4, 2003-2004 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - 2003 Jul 23, 5
      Includes information on childhood, the Henry Street Settlement, Lillian Wald, the Army, nursing in the 1950s, Yale School of Nursing in the 1950s, Virginia Henderson, and Cicely Saunders, among other topics.
      - Use copy, 1 compact disc (CD-R) (Box 5U)
    - 2004 Jul 9, 9
      Includes information on Florence's family, medical science and nursing in the early 20th century, New Haven in the 1960s, and the Yale School of Nursing, among other topics.
      - Use copy, 2 (Box 6U–7U)
    - 2004 Jul 23, 8
      Includes information on Henry Wald's decline and Alzheimers, and how Florence and Henry met and their early life together, among other topics.
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 8U)